<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Florian Raichle</title><link>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Florian Raichle</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simulation of adsorption on moving particles using the Eulerian-Eulerian lattice Boltzmann method</title><link>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/thesis/</guid><description>Abstract To simulate adsorption in industrial applications and gain more insight into the coupling of fluid flow and adsorption performance, adsorption models at larger scales than just single particles are needed. In this thesis a model of the adsorption on moving particles is applied to the lattice Boltzmann method using an Euler-Euler approach. The adsorption model is based on mass transfer as described by the linear driving force model and can incorporate several mass transfer mechanisms, such as film diffusion, surface diffusion and pore diffusion.</description></item><item><title>Simulation of adsorption on moving particles using the Eulerian-Eulerian lattice Boltzmann method html</title><link>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/master-thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/master-thesis/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html> Simulation of adsorption on moving particles using the Eulerian-Eulerian lattice Boltzmann method Simulation of adsorption on moving particles using the Eulerian-Eulerian lattice Boltzmann method html Florian Raichle
November 08, 2021 - May 23, 2022
Abstract To simulate adsorption in industrial applications and gain more insight into the coupling of fluid flow and adsorption performance, adsorption models at larger scales than just single particles are needed. In this thesis a model of the adsorption on moving particles is applied to the lattice Boltzmann method using an Euler-Euler approach.</description></item><item><title>Hugo Theme</title><link>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/theme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/theme/</guid><description>A theme for the static website builder Hugo using tailwindcss and alpine.js. It is based on an existing theme but refactored, the css rewritten using tailwind and customized for my needs to explore the possibilities of Hugo and tailwind.
How to use the theme The code can be found on my github.
Follow the hugo&amp;rsquo;s quick start guide and clone the theme from https://github.com/FlorianRaichle/my-hugo-profile.git. Build on the example page in the website folder inside the theme.</description></item><item><title>Rohrpost</title><link>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/rohrpost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlorianRaichle.github.io/projects/rohrpost/</guid><description>If you have a link, snippet of text or an image you just want to get from one device to another, use Rohrpost. It syncs instantly between all of your devices. The goal was to find a simple starter project to have a go at app development. I was using Windows and iOS and wanted an easy way to share small amounts of data between the two operating systems, without having to email myself.</description></item></channel></rss>